[Music]
welcome only eight of you remain and
once again the teams are even foreign
team Peck and foreign team Nunez this
week we are testing technical
application technical application is
what's happening when you put the needle
to the skin is your line work clean is
your shading smooth with this flash
challenge you must tattoo one of the
most delicate and sensitive areas of the
human body the palm of the hand there
are more sensory neurons on the palms
than any other part of the body and a
larger brain area devoted to receiving
their signals it means your canvas will
definitely be an excruciating pain
getting your palm tattooed is one of the
most complicated serious areas it's
extremely painful and it's not like
normal tattooing you must have flawless
technical application overwork the skin
and you'll damage it permanently under
work it and your tattoo won't hold
anybody have their palms tattooed
anybody have done it before
there is a right way to tattoo a pom and
a definite load of wrong ways I don't
know the technique I don't even know
where to start let's meet your canvases
[Music]
canvases please tell us what you'd like
tattooed in your palm traditional black
and gray eyeball with a teardrop call a
traditional Sacred Heart not going to
happen color tattoos are impossible on
the palm they're not going to stick
color realistic tiger fish colorful
realistic made a fighting fish can't
really do realism in the hand their
expectations are way wrong a Yeti in
color new-school deal traditional planet
Earth 3d crystal ball he'll know
everybody's have to do somethin Essen
today to get those counts to something
more realistic ok canvases one by one
please draw a skull the name on the
bottom of your skull will determine your
artist go ahead
Nicky Ryan sketchy lawyer a lionfish
realistic on the palm of her hand in
color completely undoable Gian Nate bone
face Kevin Kelley as you know the winner
of this flash challenge will have the
power to assign all human canvases in
the Elimination tattoo you have three
hours to tattoo your canvases palm and
your time starts now
Double Trouble right palm tattoos are
incredibly difficult because the skin
type is completely different the only
thing that stays on the palm is flat
it's always being used the skins always
peeling always changing color with this
thing is impossible I'm gonna put you
through so much pain for nothing
palm tattoos are all about specialized
technical application and it's something
that has to be deep anything around here
where the calluses start to begin it
will fall out today Oliver and I are not
gonna help whatsoever this is something
that either as a tattooer you know how
to do or you don't and we're not here to
teach that to him we're here to critique
it here's the thing with the hands you
got to make it a little bit simpler no
gotta stay closer to realistic
there's no way she's not gonna do colors
today I'm just gonna have to deal it
it's not something when you have eight
tattooers in a room and not a single one
has their palms tattooed think about it
yeah how bad could upon actually be you
know pretty bad
so Kelly when you did your palm tattoo
do you go in just kind of like it's
pretty similar to like lining making my
lines with sibling you're badass I'm
more than happy to help Nikki and Ryan
we just need one of the girls to get the
skull pick hey Kelly where do you think
I should stipple just like a little
under hair yeah that weights like on it
depth
okay yes I am really proud of my ladies
right now our campuses are all
compromising on a realistic design I'll
veto their canvases that good color
stuff in their palms I'm not gonna last
we are about to make these boys look
like fools
five four three two one
that's it machines down time is up no
more ink Oh little moment of pain for a
lifetime of pretty sketchy give her
something that looks like she put her
hand in an ink spill or something what
even is that are you happy yeah okay all
right artists it is time to critique
your work bone face it's a smooth tattoo
it was on a regular part of the body
that nice smooth gray shading is a
beautiful effect but you can see the
texture of the skin that has the
fingerprint texture you can see that
shading is just sitting on top of that
that's the skin that dies in a tattoo
process so when that skin dies and
leaves the tattoos leaving with it so
for that point your technical
application on a regular part of the
body is fine but in this challenge it
didn't hold up Kevin
would be questionable how he'll
typically you're not creating enough
depth when you just come with one pass
no matter how slow or how deep so
typically it tends not to hold and you
see when you try to outline on that skin
it's not like normal skin when you run
the needle across it it just doesn't
come out looking crisp and it's gonna
heal even worse
the judges are showing no mercy I'm
consumed by fear right now Kelly I
really like to design very simple I like
the approach this is the way to do it
when it heals it will still look like
the world obviously the oil of the day
is that detail isn't gonna hold colors
not gonna hold so you can pretty much
omit all that and just get in and get
out thank you
Jian what we're looking at right now is
the beautiful tattoo but I don't know
what percentage is gonna be there when
it heals it's gonna be a very low
percentage so low that people are not
gonna be able to recognize what it is
Nate I've done a few palm tattoos
I know colors about decision to make but
that you put color I couldn't talk him
out of it the fact of the matter is is
that tattoo doesn't look right now and
it's not gonna look good later Ryan I
know that to get a palm tattoo to say it
has to be as simple as it possibly can
be I really like the design I really
like the simplicity of it and I like the
way it fits the hand but the majority of
your dots you can see that they're just
not deep enough chances are it's gonna
be the disappearing tattoo Niki the
approach used in this tattoo is
definitely the right technical
application the ones that stay the ones
that are done like this very legible
clean design the placement I do wish
that you came down a little lower made
the flame a little more pronounced but
the execution is very clean the route
that you chose is the only route that
will stay sketchy I think it should stay
pretty good it's not it's a huge black
spot in those lines that's just a bunch
of pain for nothing
it's hard to see what's going on looking
up at it close the detail is very
stretchy if I did the tattoo that big it
would have been hard to read it's just a
mess man I know that I'm a great
tattooer getting put on blast I'm not
used to that and I don't like it
right guys today we're testing technical
application with palm tattoos the top
three for me is obvious the girls Nikki
did one of the best Nikki understood
what they're supposed to look like her
technical application was spot-on and
her technique was right and if Kelly
would have went the same approach with
the line weight that Nikki had and the
bigger dots I think it would have been a
bigger punch as far as design goes
Ryan's is one of my favorite of the day
at least
Ryan Nikki and Kelly all took the right
approach let's let him know all right
guys today you had to show flawless
technical application by tattooing your
canvases palm judges have decided the
winner of today's Flash challenge
hey this Oliver Peck be sure to
subscribe to Spike's YouTube for more
eek master videos